American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 10, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Martin, Artemas, 1835-1918
    Washington, D.C. A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for list of members. Asks for copy of Constitution and By-laws.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 10, 1899; 9x5-1/2; Pemberton, Henry, 1826-1911
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Presents set of Bischof's Chemische Geologie to A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 11, 1899; 8x5; Armstrong, W. G. (William George), Baron, 1810-1900
    L.in 3rd.P. Presents supplement to his work.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 11, 1899; 5x8; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 1p., end. Requests copy of S.S. Haldeman's paper on Pennsylvania German Vernacular. Not A.P.S. publication?
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 11, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States Naval Observatory.
    Washington, Typed L.S.: W[illia]m Harkness 1p. Concerns its publications needed by A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 12, 1899; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. wanting Concerns Smithsonian and the package for R.H. Mathews.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 12, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p. Calls meeting of Conversazione Committee.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 14, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Missed meeting by mistake in time.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 14, 1899; 9x8; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. of receipt Concerns paper order for Pepper Memorial.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 16, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    [Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Cannot attend meeting of committee on Conversazione.
  - Letter to J[sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, April 17, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Drexel Institute of Technology. Graduate School of Library Science
    Phila., A.L.S.: Alice B[ertha] Kroeger 1p. Asks to bring library school class for visit.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 17, 1899; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns "Mexican Picture Book" to be sold at Quaritch's Refers to Crawford MSS.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays; Phila.], April 19, 1899; 9x5-1/2; Learned, Marion Dexter, 1857-1917
    A.L.S. 1p. Will see Franklin letters. Refers to Pastorius.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], April 19, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Robins, James W.
    Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to L.A. Sadeler [sic, Samuel Phillip Sadtler], April 20, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Myers, George William, b. 1864
    Urbana, Ill., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his translation of Seeliger's work on photometry.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 21, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Conradson, P. H.
    Franklin, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Orders copies of papers on petroleum by S.P. Sadtler and S.F. Peckham.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 21, 1899; 6-1/2x8; Munro, Dana Carleton, 1866-1933
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Vol. 5 of series is ready to send.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 22, 1899; 9-1/2x6; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his memoir of E.D. Cope. For printed memoir, see: APS. Addresses in honor of E.D. Cope, Nov. 12, 1897.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 22, 1899; 9x6; Sadtler, Samuel P. (Samuel Philip), 1847-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Concerns Frazer's obituary notice of Cope.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, April 22, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS., S. with stamp: John Hay 2p. Concerns copy of "Digest and history of international arbitrations" requested for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, April 23, 1899.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], April 22, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Superintendent of Documents
    Washington, Typed L. with MS. addition 1p. Sending copy of "Flags of maritime nations" for A.P.S. library, as requested by Boies Penrose.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, April 22, 1899; 8x5; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asks about papers published by R.A. Tilghman.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 24, 1899; 8-1/2x6; Sadtler, Samuel P. (Samuel Philip), 1847-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns box of MSS. for G.W. Myers.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 25, 1899; 7-1/2x5; Hall, George R., b. 1818
    New York, A.L. 2p., end. Inquiry about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 25, 1899; 9x6; Thomson, John, 1835-1916
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks for copies of Pepper memorial pamphlet.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays, April 26, 1899; 8x5; Mitchell, James T. (James Tyndale), 1834-1915
    Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Arrangements for meeting suit him.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] M[inis] Hays, April 26, 1899; 10x8; United States. Weather Bureau
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Willis L[uther] Moore 1p., end. Publications have been sent as requested.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 29, 1899; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Geological Survey of Alabama
    University, Ala., Typed L.S.: Eugene A. Smith 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends copy of W.B. Phillips' report on iron making for A.P.S. library. Encloses list of Survey publications.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, May 2, 1899; 9x6; Thomson, John, 1835-1916
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for copy of Pepper memorial pamphlet.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morrison [sic, Morison], May 3, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Stellwagen, Thomas Cook, 1841-1918
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends summary of his remarks (about Carthaginian stela). For printed summary, see: APS Proceedings, vol.38, pp.71-74.
  - Receipt for mineral specimens deposited by A.P.S., May 3, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Wagner Free Institute of Science
    Phila., Typed D.S.: Thomas L[ynch] Montgomery, C[harles] W[illiston] Johnson 1p.
  - Letter to W[illiam] B[erryman] Scott, May 4, 1899; 5-1/2x8; Case, E. C. (Ermine Cowles), b. 1871
    Milwaukee, Wis., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns illustrations for paper.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 4, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Walker, Lewis Burd, 1855-1903
    Pottsville, Pa., A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Sending v.2 of Burd papers.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 5, 1899; 8x5; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Thompson, Heber S. (Heber Samuel), 1840-1911
    Pottsville, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends payment for 1899 Proceedings.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, May 5, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States National Museum
    Washington, Typed L.S.: F[rederick] W[illiam] True 2p. Sending v.2-4 of Museum Proceedings for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic, Hays, May 8, 1899; 8x5; Dixon, Samuel Gibson, 1851-1918
    Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges election as Councillor to fill term of I.J. Wistar.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], May 8, 1899; 6-1/2x8; Munro, Dana Carleton, 1866-1933
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns enclosed envelope which arrived empty and unsealed.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis [sic, Minis] Hays, May 8, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks to have Conversazione invitations sent to H.W. Dubois and W. Weinrich.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 8, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Superintendent of Documents
    Washington, Typed L.S.: L.C. Ferrell 1p. Cannot supply Weather Bureau publications for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 9, 1899; 9x5-1/2; Merrick, John Vaughan, 1828?-1906
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerns correspondence of John Vaughan.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 9, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Scott, Dunbar D.
    Ironwood, Mich., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper on mine surveying instruments. Refers to H. Draper, Rittenhouse.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 9, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Apologizes for delay in reply. Encloses letter of explanation from E.C. Case. For enclosure, see E.C. Case to W.B. Scott, May 4, 1899.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays], May 9, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Willis, Henry, 1852?-1933
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asks to have Conversazione invitation sent to Eugene Castello.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 10, 1899; 10x8i; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. Concerns shipment of exchanges from St. Petersburg.
  - Memorandum to [A.P.S.] about package of exchange publications, May 10, 1899; 8x5-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed D. 1p.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 10, 1899; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Trübner, Karl J.
    Strassburg, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends proof of A.P.S. entry in Minerva for correction and return.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, May 11, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Adams, Robert, 1849-1906
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns government publication for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 11, 1899; 9x8; Hart, Edward, 1854-
    Easton, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. Requests papers for Hans Hoefer: S.P. Sadtler on petroleum and natural gas, S.F. Peckham on the genesis of bitumens. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp.93-140, and 37, pp.108-139.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 13, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p. Give bearer specimens for W.H. Wahl.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 13, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 16, 1899; 9x6; Cleemann, Richard A. (Richard Alsop), 1840-1912
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns writing up of Minutes. Refers to R.A. Tilghman.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 17, 1899; 10-1/2x8; American Association for the Advancement of Science
    Typed L.S.: E[dwin] G[rant] Conklin, Edwin S[chofield] Crawley 1p. Concerns plans for Association meeting in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 17, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Asks about Lavoisier's paper on street-lighting. Can it be obtained in publications of French Academy?
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 19, 1899; 5-1/2x8; Rogers, Albert T.
    East Last Vegas, N.M., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of G.H. Smith's paper, "Theory of the state." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, v.34, pp.181-332.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 20, 1899; 9-1/2x6; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for MS. of his memoir of E.D. Cope. For printed memoir, see: APS. Addresses in honor of E.D. Cope, Nov. 12, 1897.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 22, 1899; 9x5-1/2; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Atlantic City, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns P. Frazer's paper (obituary of E.D. Cope?)
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 22, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Stevenson, Sara Yorke, 1847-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copies of Pepper memorial volumes, one for Phoebe A. Hearst, "one of Dr. Pepper's truest friends and in whose house he died."
  - Letter to Samuel P[hillip] Sadtler, May 23, 1899; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] L. 1p. Will attend to business referred to him.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, May 23, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Adjutant-General's Office
    Washington, Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A[ugustus] Simpson 1p. Requested copies of "Military notes on the Philippines" and "Selected professional papers" have been sent to the A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, May 26, 1899.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, May 23, 1899; 10-1/2x8, 1-1/2x8-1/2; United States. Office of Naval Intelligence
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richardson Glover 1p. Enc. Returns I.M. Hays's memorandum about copy of War Notes, no.5, for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to Hays, May 25, 1899.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 24, 1899; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell 1p. Enc. wanting Sends proof for decision. Asks about standing type. Refers to Frazer, Keiser's paper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 24, 1899; 9x6; Stevenson, Sara Yorke, 1847-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for Pepper memorial pamphlets.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 25, 1899; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] L. 2p. Concerns obituary of Alexander Biddle to be prepared by H.C. Baird, the meeting of the Amer. Assoc. for Adv. of Science, and H.F. Jayne.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 26, 1899; 11x8; Garrett, Philip C. (Philip Cresson), 1834-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns search for issues of Haverford College Studies for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 26, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Haupt, Lewis M. (Lewis Muhlenberg), b. 1844
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Defers to Fraley's advice.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 26, 1899; 4x5; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., A.L. on card S. 2p., end. Lists his pamphlets which should be in A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 27, 1899; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proof and discusses charges.
  - Memorandum about John Vaughan papers, May 29, 1899; 9x6; Merrick, John Vaughan, 1828?-1906
    Phila., A.D.S. 1p. Has divided papers, part for the Unitarian Society and part for himself, as directed by the A.P.S. on May 5, 1899.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, May 30, 1899; 9x6; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 2p. Will serve on committee for Phila. meeting of American Association for Advancement of Science.
  - Receipt for papers left by John Vaughan, May 31, 1899; 9-1/2x6; First Congregational Society of Unitarian Christians in the City of Philadelphia
    Phila., D.S.: Joseph May, Pastor 1p. Papers delivered to church in accordance with A.P.S. resolution of May 5, 1899.
  - Invitation to A.P.S. to attend unveiling of monument to Giuseppe Meneghini, June 2, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Comitato monumento Meneghini
    Pisa, Printed D. filled in in Ms. 1p. and add.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, June 5, 1899; 8x5; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Returns proof of obituary of R.A. Tilghman.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], June 9, 1899; 8x5; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: James G Barnwell 1p. Concerns F. Prime's Catalogue of Official Reports upon Geological Surveys...1879.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], June 10, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    Phila. A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Concerns duplicates of his catalogue of geological reports.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, June 14, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Andrew H[ussey] Allen 1p. Concerns copy of "Proclamations and decrees during war with Spain" for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, June 15, 1899.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 17, 1899; 10-1/2X8; MacDonald, Arthur, 1856-1936
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1P.,end. Presents copy of his "Experimental study of children" to A.P.S. library, through Commissioner of Education.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic, Hays], June 17, 1899; 8-1/2x5; Trumbull, H. Clay (Henry Clay), 1830-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for address of H.C. Bolton.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 20, 1899; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends proofs of C. Sellers s paper on transmission of energy by electricity. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 38, pp.49-71.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 20, 1899; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns paper for Transactions and other matters.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 20, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Public Library
    New York, Typed L.S.: J[ohn] S[haw] Billings 1p. Concerns classification system used at library.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 20, 1899; 10x8; United States. Dept. of Agriculture. Library
    Washington, Printed L. 1p. Encs. wanting Concerns proposed card catalogue of Department publications. Sends sample cards.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, June 20, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Office of Naval Intelligence
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richardson Glover 1p. Sending War Notes, no.4, for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Boies Penrose to J. Minis Hays, June 23, 1899.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 22, 1899; 8x5; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Report of attendance at Stokes Jubilee. Includes copy of his address of congratulation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 23, 1899; 10x8; Keeler, James Edward, 1857-1900
    Mount Hamilton [Calif.] A.L.S. 1p., end. Declines A.P.S. membership.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, June 23, 1899; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Forwards letter from Adjutant-General.
  - Telegram to I[saac] Minnis Hayes [sic, Minis Hays], June 24, 1899; 5-1/2x8; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Cape May, N.J., D. 1p. Phillips Committee must have access to vault.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 24, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Thomson, John, 1835-1916
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Inquires about paper on "Horologium Achaz" for Lewis Evans of London. For printed paper by J.F. Sachse, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, v.34, pp.21-30.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 26, 1899; 11x8-1/2; McPike, Eugene Fairfield, b. 1870
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 2p. Enc. Concerns his memoir of Halley. Refers to J.G. Simcoe. Encloses copy of letter to him from Alexander J. Rudolph, June 24, 1899, recommending his Halley memoir.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 27, 1899; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Stellwagen, Thomas Cook, 1841-1918
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on Carthaginian stela. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, v.38, pp.71-74.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 28, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1856-1935
    Kushequa, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks about his dues.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 30, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brown University
    Providence, R.I., L. 1p. Received his volumes of poetry for its Harris Collection of American poetry.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 4, 1899; 6-1/2x5-1/2; Goodfellow, Julia S.
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 3p. Death of husband, Edward Goodfellow.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 5, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends payment for subscription to Proceedings.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minas [sic, Minis] Hays, July 7, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Public Library
    New York, Typed L. 1p. Sending copy of library's classification system as directed by J.S. Billings.
  - Letter to F [sic, Isaac] M[inis] Hays, July 8, 1899; 11x8, 10x8; Emery, F. W. R.
    Taunton, Mass., Typed L.S. 1p. 2 encs. Concerns his process for preserving old books and papers. Is A.P.S. interested? Encloses printed advertisement and a letter of recommendation.
  - Letter to E[lla M] Morison, July 10, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brown University
    Providence, R.I., L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for copy of H. Phillips' translation of German lyrics.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morrisson [sic, Morison], July 10, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] L. in 3d person 1p., end. Asks for letters from G. Gray.
  - Letter to L[ewis] M[uhlenberg] Haupt, July 12, 1899; 7-1/2x6; Jenkins, William Dunbar, -1914
    Natchez, Miss., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends sketch of Wm. Dunbar's life. Asks for copy of his paper on Mississippi River. For printed paper, see: APS transactions, o.s., vol.6, pp.165-187. On same sheet is Haupt to [A.P.S.] July 17, 1899.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, July 14, 1899; 3-1/2x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Concerns H. Pettit and sketch of Emma Seiler in Proceedings.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], July 17, 1899; 7-1/2x6; Haupt, Lewis M. (Lewis Muhlenberg), b. 1844
    Belmar, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Forwards request of W.D. Jenkins for copy of W. Dunbar's paper on Mississippi river. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, o.s., vol.6, pp.165-187. Written on same sheet as Jenkins to Haupt, July 12, 1899.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, July 19, 1899; 10x8; United States. Dept. of the Treasury
    Washington, Typed L.S.: H. A. Taylor. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Returns memorandum from I.M. Hays. Sending copy of D.S. Jordan's report on fur seals for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, July 24, 1899.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, July 20, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Andrew H[ussey] Allen 1p. Sending copy of "Freedom of private property on sea from capture during war" to A.P.S. library, as requested. With covering letter from Penrose to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 21, 1899.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 22, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns copy of War Department reports on tests of metals, for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], July 25, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Knortz, Karl, 1841-1918
    Evansville, Ind. A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Asks about papers by W.J. Hoffman.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 25, 1899; 9x8; MacCalla & co.
    Typed L. 1p. Sends for packages to go to Smithsonian.
  - Letter to the Secretary of War, July 25, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. by various Army departments Concerns copies of War Department tests of metals for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 26, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns copies of War Department tests of metals for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 27, 1899; 11x8; Weaver, E. A.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks about papers by Walter J. Hoffman on grammatical notes and folk medicine of the Pennsylvania Germans. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, v.26, pp.187-285, 329-352.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays; Phila.], July 31, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    A.L. on postal card s. 1p. and add. Asks to meet Hays at the Hall.
  - Letter to J[sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, July 31, 1899; 9-1/2x8; Jenkins, William Dunbar, -1914
    Ardsleyon-Hudson, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of W. Dunbar's paper on Mississipi River. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, o.s., vol.6, pp.165-187.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], July, 1899; 8x5, 9x11-1/2; Royal Photographic Society of Great Britain
    London, Printed L. 1p., end. Enc. Change of address. Encloses new mailing labels.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; León, Nicolás, 1859-1929
    Mexico City, Printed L. on postal card 1p. and add. Change of address.